<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eckhart Spalding</title>
    <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eckhart Spalding</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mwanakijiji.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>9th Australian Exoplanet Workshop</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2023/10/02/aew9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2023/10/02/aew9/</guid>
      <description>We had a terrific couple days at USYD at the 9th Australian Exoplanet workshop&amp;ndash; the first such workshop after the worst of the Covid pandemic. There were some sixty-five in-person participants, and about ten more online, with a program featuring talks, a poster session, collaborative sessions, and a panel discussion about the future of the field.&#xA;Above: Sergio on the power and promise of photonic lanterns.&#xA;A few of the highlights featured Marshall Perrin&amp;rsquo;s talk &amp;ldquo;Imaging Planetary Systems with JWST,&amp;rdquo; Sergio Leon-Saval&amp;rsquo;s talk (and demo!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-generation college students in astronomy</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2023/06/16/first_gens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2023/06/16/first_gens/</guid>
      <description>Astrobites.org has posted an article based on my interviews with first-generation college students, and others who have faced more adversity on their journey than is commonly known or talked about. Read the article here. My thanks go to the interviewees for sharing their experiences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling exozodiacal dust</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2022/04/01/phys-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2022/04/01/phys-today/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve put out an article in Physics Today about the story of nulling interferometry to characterize the exozodiacal dust population. Read all about it here.&#xA;The above photo of the Large Binocular Telescope backdropped by the Milky Way was taken by Ryan Ketterer, and Steve Ertel added in the cone of light on the right-hand side to illustrate the disk of zodiacal dust in our own solar system&amp;mdash; which in reality is outside the frame of this image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The quest for exoplanet direct imaging with ELT apertures</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2022/03/18/exoexplorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2022/03/18/exoexplorer/</guid>
      <description>Here is the video recording of my talk &amp;ldquo;The quest for exoplanet direct imaging with ELT apertures,&amp;rdquo; part of the NASA ExoExplorer 2022 science series.&#xA;Abstract: Direct imaging of exoplanets is a promising route to finding and characterizing exoplanets in the thermal infrared. Currently the technique is most sensitive to massive, young planets on wide orbits. Innovative observing techniques are necessary to probe smaller angles from host stars, or search for older or lower-mass planets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Universe Revealed</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2021/11/30/our-universe-revealed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2021/11/30/our-universe-revealed/</guid>
      <description>Here is the video recording of my talk &amp;ldquo;Seeing the Light: Hunting for solar systems like our own,&amp;rdquo; part of the University of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s public science talk series Our Universe Revealed.&#xA;Abstract: A group of astronomers recently carried out a survey of nearby stars, called the “Hunt for Observable Signatures of Terrestrial Systems.” The survey used the Large Binocular Telescope in Arizona to measure the faint signals of dust around stars and provide the first realistic hints of discovering Earth-like planets around other stars using future space-based missions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krapf&#39;s 1857 account of the Maasai</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2021/09/30/krapf-1857/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2021/09/30/krapf-1857/</guid>
      <description>My mom and I have translated one of the oldest published accounts of the Maasai. It is the article &amp;ldquo;A short description of the Masai and Wakwafi tribes in southeast Africa&amp;rdquo; which appeared in the journal Das Ausland (Abroad) in 1857. The author was Johann Krapf, a missionary who lived in a village inland from Mombasa from 1846 to 1853. From there, he made a number of travels deep into the East African interior in what is now Kenya and Tanzania.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me I&amp;rsquo;m originally from downstate Illinois, where I dropped out of high school and went to college. From time to time I have bounced around between four continents. In my free time I enjoy scuba diving, international travel, excellent writing, and the great outdoors.&#xA;Above: I also enjoy ham radio, and made a WSPR (low-power) radio beacon with a dipole antenna and a Raspberry Pi in my apartment. This image shows a sample of contacts it made in a one-hour period at a wavelength of 20 meters, while consuming 2 watts&amp;mdash; just a little more than a MacBook in sleep mode.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>[CV] Last update: Dec. 12, 2024</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/kenya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/kenya/</guid>
      <description>Krapf, J. 1857. &amp;ldquo;A short description of the Masai and Wakwafi tribes in southeast Africa&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/notes/</guid>
      <description>Go 语言学习笔记 Envoy 学习笔记 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/reading_list/</guid>
      <description>2024:&#xA;Ice Ghosts: The Epic Hunt for the Lost Franklin Expedition (Paul Watson)&#xA;On Call: A Doctor&amp;rsquo;s Journey in Public Service (Anthony Fauci)&#xA;The Fight of His Life: Inside Joe Biden&amp;rsquo;s White House (Chris Whipple)&#xA;The Songlines (Bruce Chadwick)&#xA;The Internationalists: The Fight to Restore American Foreign Policy After Trump (Alexander Ward)&#xA;Challenger: A True Story of Heroism and Disaster on the Edge of Space (Adam Higginbotham)&#xA;Knife: Meditations After an Attempted Murder (Salman Rushdie)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>[ADS Publications]&#xA;I am a postdoc at the University of Sydney, where I work on the GLINT nulling interferometer instrument on the Subaru Telescope. GLINT uses integrated photonics technology to miniaturize what used to only be done with bulk optics, and our Australia-based GLINT gang is pushing the technology to ever greater science capabilities.&#xA;From 2020 to 2023 I was a postdoc in Jeff Chilcote&amp;rsquo;s research lab at the University of Notre Dame, where I was in charge of testing and upgrading components of the Gemini Planet Imager instrument in preparation for installing it on the Gemini-North telescope in Hawaii.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/search/placeholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/search/placeholder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Posts Archive</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/archive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
