<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eckhart&#39;s site</title>
    <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eckhart&#39;s site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mwanakijiji.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/personal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 12:15:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/personal/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m originally from downstate Illinois, where I dropped out of high school and went to college. From time to time I have bounced around between three continents.
In my free time I enjoy scuba diving, ham radio, international travel, reading excellent writing (here is a reading list), and the great outdoors.
Above: Curt (K7ZOO) listening to satellite transmissions from somewhere near Sonoita, Arizona, during an expedition of the K7UAZ ham radio group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading list</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 12:15:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/reading_list/</guid>
      <description>Here are some books I&amp;rsquo;ve read in the past few years.
2021:
A Promised Land (Barack Obama)
The British in Mombasa, 1824-1826: Being the History of Captain Owen&amp;rsquo;s Protectorate (John Gray)\
2020:
Secondhand Time: The Last of the Soviets (Svetlana Alexievich)
The Hubble Wars (Eric Chaisson)
Armageddon: The Battle for Germany, 1944-1945 (Max Hastings)
A Very Stable Genius: Donald J. Trump&amp;rsquo;s Testing of America (Carol D. Leonnig and Philip Rucker)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 12:14:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>I am a postdoc in Jeff Chilcote&amp;rsquo;s research lab at the University of Notre Dame, where I am in charge of testing and upgrading components of the Gemini Planet Imager instrument in preparation for installing it on the Gemini-North telescope in Hawaii. The motivation of this upgrade is to survey for massive planets with low initial starting entropies (i.e., cool planets), and thereby provide additional constraints on the physics of planet formation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
