<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Eckhart Spalding</title>
    <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Eckhart Spalding</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mwanakijiji.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>9th Australian Exoplanet Workshop</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2023/10/02/aew9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2023/10/02/aew9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had a terrific couple days at USYD at the 9th Australian Exoplanet workshop&amp;ndash; the first such workshop after the worst of the&#xA;Covid pandemic. There were some sixty-five in-person participants, and about ten more online, with a&#xA;program featuring talks, a poster session, collaborative sessions, and a panel discussion about the future of the field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mwanakijiji.github.io/img/IMG_5847.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;AEW9&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Above:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;Sergio on the power and promise of photonic lanterns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few of the highlights featured Marshall Perrin&amp;rsquo;s talk &amp;ldquo;Imaging Planetary Systems with JWST,&amp;rdquo; Sergio Leon-Saval&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;talk (and demo!) about the applications of photonic lanterns for the field, and Michele Bannister&amp;rsquo;s planetary science talk&#xA;delivered from New Zealand. Other talks featured stellar activity and rotation, asteroseismology, stellar interior models, star-planet tidal evolution, stellar and planet mapping,&#xA;polarimetry of circumstellar environments, atmospheric chemistry of Hot Jupiters, evaporating atmospheres, disk kinematics, exokuiper belts,&#xA;transits photometry to learn about both the planet and the star, astrometry, software, astrophotonics, and new missions and facilities&amp;mdash; like the TOLIMAN&#xA;satellite currently under development to perform interferometric astrometry on the nearest star system to hunt for planets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-generation college students in astronomy</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2023/06/16/first_gens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2023/06/16/first_gens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Astrobites.org has posted an article based on my interviews with first-generation college students, and others who have faced more adversity on their journey than is commonly known or talked about. Read the article &lt;a href=&#34;https://astrobites.org/2023/05/16/rise-of-the-first-gens/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. My thanks go to the interviewees for sharing their experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling exozodiacal dust</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2022/04/01/phys-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2022/04/01/phys-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve put out an article in &lt;em&gt;Physics Today&lt;/em&gt; about the story of nulling interferometry&#xA;to characterize the exozodiacal dust population. Read all about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://physicstoday.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/PT.3.4982&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above photo of the Large Binocular Telescope backdropped by the Milky Way was taken by &lt;a href=&#34;https://ryanketterer.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan Ketterer&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;and Steve Ertel added in the cone of light on the right-hand side to illustrate the disk of zodiacal dust in our own solar system&amp;mdash;&#xA;which in reality is outside the frame of this image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The quest for exoplanet direct imaging with ELT apertures</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2022/03/18/exoexplorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2022/03/18/exoexplorer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is the video recording of my talk &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VH0kVXDlz-Y&amp;amp;t=1s&#34;&gt;The quest for exoplanet direct imaging with ELT apertures&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo;&#xA;part of the NASA ExoExplorer 2022 science series.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abstract: &lt;em&gt;Direct imaging of exoplanets is a promising route to finding and characterizing exoplanets in the thermal infrared. Currently the technique is most sensitive to massive, young planets on wide orbits. Innovative observing techniques are necessary to probe smaller angles from host stars, or search for older or lower-mass planets. The Large Binocular Telescope (LBT) is in a unique position to push these frontiers in preparation for the era of 30-m-class extremely large telescopes. When light is combined coherently in a &amp;ldquo;Fizeau&amp;rdquo; mode between the LBT&amp;rsquo;s twin 8.4-m sub-telescopes, the facility effectively becomes a masked 22.7-m telescope. I will present an observation of the nearby star Altair in this mode, which represents the first LBT Fizeau dataset with a degree of automated phase control. These data constrain the existence of companions of 1.3 M⊙ down to an inner angle of ≈0.15&amp;quot;, closer than any previously published direct imaging of Altair. I outline ways forward, in terms of software and physical upgrades, and post-processing with longer integration times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Universe Revealed</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2021/11/30/our-universe-revealed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2021/11/30/our-universe-revealed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mwanakijiji.github.io/img/revealed.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Our Universe Revealed&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is the video recording of my talk &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-gKKHhJsuMY&#34;&gt;Seeing the Light: Hunting for solar systems like our own&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo;&#xA;part of the University of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s public science talk series &lt;em&gt;Our Universe&#xA;Revealed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abstract: &lt;em&gt;A group of astronomers recently carried out a survey of nearby stars, called the “Hunt for Observable Signatures of Terrestrial Systems.” The survey used the Large Binocular Telescope in Arizona to measure the faint signals of dust around stars and provide the first realistic hints of discovering Earth-like planets around other stars using future space-based missions. Postdoctoral researcher Eckhart Spalding, who participated in the survey, will describe the adventure, the innovation, the science, and the future implications of this pioneering survey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krapf&#39;s 1857 account of the Maasai</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2021/09/30/krapf-1857/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/2021/09/30/krapf-1857/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mwanakijiji.github.io/img/krapf_blog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krapf&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My mom and I have translated one of the oldest published accounts of the Maasai. It is the article &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mwanakijiji.github.io/doc/krapf_1857_ausland.pdf&#34;&gt;A short description of the Masai and Wakwafi tribes in southeast&#xA;Africa&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; which appeared in the journal &lt;em&gt;Das Ausland&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;(&lt;em&gt;Abroad&lt;/em&gt;) in 1857. The author was Johann Krapf, a missionary who lived in a village inland&#xA;from Mombasa from 1846 to 1853. From there, he made a number of travels deep into the&#xA;East African interior in what is now Kenya and Tanzania. He was the first such traveler, native or foreign,&#xA;to write a detailed and lengthy first-hand account of the East African interior, which was published in&#xA;1858 in the two-volume set &lt;em&gt;Reisen in Ost-Afrika&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Travels in East Africa&lt;/em&gt;). (Krapf also holds the distinction of being the first person to ever mention the Maasai in writing at all, in a letter from 1846.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
