<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Eckhart&#39;s site</title>
    <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Eckhart&#39;s site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mwanakijiji.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling exozodiacal light</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/blog/phys_today/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/blog/phys_today/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve put out an article in Physics Today about the story of nulling interferometry to characterize the exozodiacal dust population. Read all about it here.
(The above photo of the Large Binocular Telescope backdropped by the Milky Way was taken by Ryan Ketterer, and Steve Ertel added in the cone of light on the right-hand side to illustrate the disk of zodiacal dust in our own solar system&amp;mdash; which in reality is outside the frame of this image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeing the Light</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/blog/univ_revealed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/blog/univ_revealed/</guid>
      <description>Here is the video recording of my talk &amp;ldquo;Seeing the Light: Hunting for solar systems like our own,&amp;rdquo; part of the University of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s public science talk series Our Universe Revealed. The talk abstract is as follows:
A group of astronomers recently carried out a survey of nearby stars, called the “Hunt for Observable Signatures of Terrestrial Systems.” The survey used the Large Binocular Telescope in Arizona to measure the faint signals of dust around stars and provide the first realistic hints of discovering Earth-like planets around other stars using future space-based missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An early account of the Maasai</title>
      <link>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/blog/krapf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mwanakijiji.github.io/blog/krapf/</guid>
      <description>I have translated one of the oldest published accounts of the Maasai (with careful proofreading from my mom). It is the article &amp;ldquo;A short description of the Masai and Wakwafi tribes in southeast Africa&amp;rdquo; which appeared in the journal Das Ausland (Abroad) in 1857. The author was Johann Krapf, a missionary who lived in a village inland from Mombasa from 1846 to 1853. From there, he made a number of travels deep into the East African interior in what is now Kenya and Tanzania.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
